<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chip Senkbeil</title>
    <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chip Senkbeil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chipsenkbeil.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down the Zsh Notes Function</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I discussed my need to have method to jot down notes quickly and comfortably on a computer. I wanted the setup to be as painless as possible while also giving me the flexibility I desired to extend the note-taking method.
Being a lightweight user of zsh - not leveraging many plugins or additional functionality - I decided to explore writing a zsh function to be exposed in my shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Barrier to Entry in Note Taking</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest challenges to accomplishing something is the barrier to entry. Starting a project, exercising, and even writing this blog post take genuine effort for me to do. After realizing this as one of my biggest obstacles to getting things done, I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated quite a few cycles of my time toward figuring out ways to reduce the initial friction. For the case of taking notes, this involved both providing a quick way to get started as well as a comfortable environment to write notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxmox Changes</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/promox-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/promox-changes/</guid>
      <description>Removing subscription notice sed -i.bak &amp;#39;s/NotFound/Active/g&amp;#39; /usr/share/perl5/PVE/API2/Subscription.pm &amp;amp;&amp;amp; systemctl restart pveproxy.service Generating Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt certs https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/HTTPS_Certificate_Configuration_(Version_4.x_and_newer)#Let.27s_Encrypt_using_acme.sh
Supporting port 80 &amp;amp; 443 By default, proxmox looks for traffic only on port 8006. Based on my readings online, forcefully changing the port - which is now hardcoded - can cause a lot of problems. Instead, the most recent and successful recommendation has been to use nginx to redirect traffic on port 80 and 443 to port 8006.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Github</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/search-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 20:51:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/search-github/</guid>
      <description>Couple of notes about searching on Github that have proven to be quite useful:
 You can include/exclude specific files using the filename property in a search.
The following searches for content &amp;ldquo;some content&amp;rdquo; only in .config files.
some content filename:.config The following searches for content &amp;ldquo;some content&amp;rdquo; in all files but .config files.
some content -filename:.config You can include/exclude specific users and organizations in a search. This is handy when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to judge how much use a library of mine is getting in the open source community while avoiding my own projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toggle Dvorak</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/toggle-dvorak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 09:36:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/toggle-dvorak/</guid>
      <description>In my ArchLinux setup with XMonad, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself wanting to swap between QWERTY and Dvorak keyboard layouts when practicing Dvorak. While my Kinesis Advantage keyboard allows me to swap layouts at the hardware level (I&amp;rsquo;m assuming by simulating Dvorak on top of Qwerty), I also found a keyboard-agnostic way to do this.
Configuring Keypress Toggle For X11, create the following configuration at /etc/X11/xorg.conf.d/00-keyboard.conf:
# Read and parsed by systemd-localed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix for XMonad with XMobar</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/fix-for-xmonad-with-xmobar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 07:49:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/fix-for-xmonad-with-xmobar/</guid>
      <description>When I updated XMonad late last year (2015), I noticed a bug where any application that I opened on my first workspace would cover XMobar.
E.g. Opening a terminal or Vivaldi took up the entire screen. The solution I found was, conveniently, located in a post on the ArchLinux forum.
Essentially, you just need to add a handleEventHook with docksEventHook and handleEventHook defaultConfig.
-- My overall config that is used elsewhere myConfig = defaultConfig { manageHook = manageDocks &amp;lt;+&amp;gt; manageHook defaultConfig , layoutHook = avoidStruts $ layoutHook defaultConfig , handleEventHook = mconcat [ docksEventHook , handleEventHook defaultConfig ] , startupHook = setWMName &amp;#34;LG3D&amp;#34; , terminal = &amp;#34;urxvtcd&amp;#34; , modMask = mod1Mask , borderWidth = 1 , focusedBorderColor = &amp;#34;blue&amp;#34; }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Masonry Layout Attempts</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</guid>
      <description>I spent two days investigating this and could not find a solution that worked. Eventually, I gave up and added the Masonry Javascript library. My two attempts were as follows:
Using CSS Columns CSS Columns enabled an easy, powerful way to spread page summaries across multiple columns. Furthermore, you can prevent page summaries from being broken up in the middle by using column-break-inside: avoid;. However, I had no way to order the page summaries dynamically such that the most recent summaries were at the top (from left to right) and older summaries were found further down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmux with XMonad Bindings</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</guid>
      <description>The Reason I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with tmux a lot lately and have come to like it quite a lot for the panes and windows - something I used quite a lot with my XMonad setup on my old Fujitsu laptop. The panes act as my individual terminals with which I can write code, read documentation, chat on IRC (using weechat or irssi), play music, etc. In other words, I do quite a lot from within terminals and being able to split up a terminal into panes (like XMonad launching tiled terminals) is quite nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blkid to get device information</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/blkid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 12:31:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/notes/blkid/</guid>
      <description>Quite often, I find myself needing to remind myself of devices connected to my computer so that I know what to type for the pmount program, which is really handy to have! The program [i]blkid[/i] is capable of doing this; however, I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for the default output and found myself using this format:
blkid -o list -c /dev/null What this does is tell the program to output the information in a user-friendly list of devices through &amp;lsquo;-o list&amp;rsquo; and not report previous devices using &amp;lsquo;-c /dev/null.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Presently employed as a Solutions Engineer at Facebook.
Employment History  Solutions Engineer; Facebook; 2017 - present Software Engineer; IBM; 2014 - 2017  Public Projects  remote.nvim; Remote File Editor; vimscript/python LINK Grus; Static Site Generator; Scala LINK Scala Debugger; Scala Tooling; Scala LINK Grid Side; Hugo Theme; JavaScript/CSS/HTML LINK Apache Toree; Scala/R/Python Spark Kernel; Scala LINK  Public Talks  Debugging in Scala; ScalaSphere, 2017; Krakow, Poland LINK Spark Kernel; Spark Meetup Bay Area, 2015; San Francisco, California LINK  Public Papers  UAV Collision Avoidance Using Artificial Potential Fields (2014) LINK Running students&amp;rsquo; software tests against each others&amp;rsquo; code: new life for an old &amp;ldquo;gimmick&amp;rdquo; (2012) LINK  Education  M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>