<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chip Senkbeil</title>
    <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chip Senkbeil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down the Zsh Notes Function</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I discussed my need to have method to jot down notes quickly and comfortably on a computer. I wanted the setup to be as painless as possible while also giving me the flexibility I desired to extend the note-taking method.
Being a lightweight user of zsh - not leveraging many plugins or additional functionality - I decided to explore writing a zsh function to be exposed in my shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Barrier to Entry in Note Taking</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest challenges to accomplishing something is the barrier to entry. Starting a project, exercising, and even writing this blog post take genuine effort for me to do. After realizing this as one of my biggest obstacles to getting things done, I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated quite a few cycles of my time toward figuring out ways to reduce the initial friction. For the case of taking notes, this involved both providing a quick way to get started as well as a comfortable environment to write notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Masonry Layout Attempts</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</guid>
      <description>I spent two days investigating this and could not find a solution that worked. Eventually, I gave up and added the Masonry Javascript library. My two attempts were as follows:
Using CSS Columns CSS Columns enabled an easy, powerful way to spread page summaries across multiple columns. Furthermore, you can prevent page summaries from being broken up in the middle by using column-break-inside: avoid;. However, I had no way to order the page summaries dynamically such that the most recent summaries were at the top (from left to right) and older summaries were found further down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmux with XMonad Bindings</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</guid>
      <description>The Reason I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with tmux a lot lately and have come to like it quite a lot for the panes and windows - something I used quite a lot with my XMonad setup on my old Fujitsu laptop. The panes act as my individual terminals with which I can write code, read documentation, chat on IRC (using weechat or irssi), play music, etc. In other words, I do quite a lot from within terminals and being able to split up a terminal into panes (like XMonad launching tiled terminals) is quite nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>