<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chip Senkbeil</title>
    <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chip Senkbeil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 16:52:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Masonry Layout Attempts</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 16:52:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</guid>
      <description>I spent two days investigating this and could not find a solution that worked. Eventually, I gave up and added the Masonry Javascript library. My two attempts were as follows:
Using CSS Columns CSS Columns enabled an easy, powerful way to spread page summaries across multiple columns. Furthermore, you can prevent page summaries from being broken up in the middle by using column-break-inside: avoid;. However, I had no way to order the page summaries dynamically such that the most recent summaries were at the top (from left to right) and older summaries were found further down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmux with XMonad Bindings</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</guid>
      <description>The Reason I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with tmux a lot lately and have come to like it quite a lot for the panes and windows - something I used quite a lot with my XMonad setup on my old Fujitsu laptop. The panes act as my individual terminals with which I can write code, read documentation, chat on IRC (using weechat or irssi), play music, etc. In other words, I do quite a lot from within terminals and being able to split up a terminal into panes (like XMonad launching tiled terminals) is quite nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>