<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chip Senkbeil</title>
    <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chip Senkbeil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying GPG and Yubikey: Part 5 (Authentication)</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-5-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-5-authentication/</guid>
      <description>As a reminder, you can check out my overview post if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about why and in what ways I started using GPG and Yubikey. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t set up your GPG keys yet, I also talk about a simple flow in my second post.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going specifically into using GPG for authentication for SSHing into remote servers and associating with Github.
Using my GPG key for authenticating over SSH One handy use case for GPG keys related to authentication is using a GPG key to access remote servers over SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying GPG and Yubikey: Part 4 (Signing)</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-4-signing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-4-signing/</guid>
      <description>As a reminder, you can check out overview post if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about why and in what ways I started using GPG and Yubikey. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t set up your GPG keys yet, I also talk about a simple flow in my second post. Finally, the email signing section expects you to have already set up encryption, so you should really check out my third post regarding encryption setup with neomutt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying GPG and Yubikey: Part 3 (Encryption)</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-3-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-3-encryption/</guid>
      <description>As a reminder, you can check out overview post if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about why and in what ways I started using GPG and Yubikey. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t set up your GPG keys yet, I also talk about a simple flow in my second post.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going specifically into using GPG for encryption and how to integrate GPG into pass and neomutt.
Refresher of current state At this point, we have our primary key for signing and certifying (SC) other keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying GPG and Yubikey: Part 2 (Setup GPG Keys)</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-2-setup-primary-gpg-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-2-setup-primary-gpg-key/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read my overview post, feel free to check it out to get an idea of why and how I started using GPG and Yubikey.
Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be diving into how to set up a new master GPG key and configure it for use with the pass utility. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ll run through the process to create subkeys with the idea of eventually storing these on Yubikeys.
Setting up a primary GPG key Although I knew I had an old key floating around from previous use, I wanted to start from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying GPG and Yubikey: Part 1 (Overview)</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-1-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/applying-gpg-and-yubikey-part-1-overview/</guid>
      <description>Today is going to be the first in a series of posts I want to write about applying GPG and YubiKey. I won&amp;rsquo;t pretend that I am an expert on either GPG or Yubikey. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on how I have been using GPG and a variety of Yubikey devices to enhance my computer experience.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to dive into GPG and YubiKey at a high level and explain what they are to my understanding and how I am using them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding My Balance</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/finding-my-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/finding-my-balance/</guid>
      <description>Writing blog posts is hard, at least for me. What is a good topic to discuss? When can I find the time to write the content? How can I stay focused long enough to finish a post? How do I understand if the post was a hit?
Interestingly enough, the challenges posed by those questions share similarities with those that I&amp;rsquo;ve faced as a Solutions Engineer, and it&amp;rsquo;s these challenges and how I&amp;rsquo;ve approached tackling them that I want to discuss now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Down the Zsh Notes Function</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/breaking-down-the-zsh-notes-function/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I discussed my need to have method to jot down notes quickly and comfortably on a computer. I wanted the setup to be as painless as possible while also giving me the flexibility I desired to extend the note-taking method.
Being a lightweight user of zsh - not leveraging many plugins or additional functionality - I decided to explore writing a zsh function to be exposed in my shell. This function&amp;rsquo;s goal was to manage my notes, providing functionality to list existing notes, create new notes, and delete old notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Barrier to Entry in Note Taking</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/reducing-the-barrier-to-entry-in-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>One of my biggest challenges to accomplishing something is the barrier to entry. Starting a project, exercising, and even writing this blog post take genuine effort for me to do. After realizing this as one of my biggest obstacles to getting things done, I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated quite a few cycles of my time toward figuring out ways to reduce the initial friction. For the case of taking notes, this involved both providing a quick way to get started as well as a comfortable environment to write notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Masonry Layout Attempts</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/css-masonry-layout-attempts/</guid>
      <description>I spent two days investigating this and could not find a solution that worked. Eventually, I gave up and added the Masonry Javascript library. My two attempts were as follows:
Using CSS Columns CSS Columns enabled an easy, powerful way to spread page summaries across multiple columns. Furthermore, you can prevent page summaries from being broken up in the middle by using column-break-inside: avoid;. However, I had no way to order the page summaries dynamically such that the most recent summaries were at the top (from left to right) and older summaries were found further down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tmux with XMonad Bindings</title>
      <link>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chipsenkbeil.com/posts/tmux-with-xmonad-bindings/</guid>
      <description>The Reason I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with tmux a lot lately and have come to like it quite a lot for the panes and windows - something I used quite a lot with my XMonad setup on my old Fujitsu laptop. The panes act as my individual terminals with which I can write code, read documentation, chat on IRC (using weechat or irssi), play music, etc. In other words, I do quite a lot from within terminals and being able to split up a terminal into panes (like XMonad launching tiled terminals) is quite nice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>